questions = [
    {
        'question': "Python, C++, and Java are considered 'High Level' languages?",
        'options': ['True','False'],
        'answer':0
    },
    {
        'question': "What is a programming Language?",
        'options': [
            "A set of instructions to perform a task",
            "A notation for specifying the steps in an algorithm that are supposed to be performed by a computer", 
            "A set of statements you generate using a programming language"
            ],
        'answer':1
    },
    {
        'question': "What is the syntax of a programming language?",
        'options': [
            'The meaning and validity of program statements',
            'The grammatical rules of the programming language', 
            ],
        'answer':1
    },
    {
        'question': "'for' and 'while' are key words that used for...",
        'options': [
            "Loops",
            "Classes",
            "Functions",
            "Conditions"
            ],
        'answer':0
    },
    {
        'question': "'def' is the key word for creating...",
        'options': [
            "Loops",
            "Classes",
            "Functions",
            "Conditions"
            ],
        'answer':2
    },
    {
        'question': "'if', 'elseif', and 'else' are all used for evaluating...",
        'options': [
            "Loops",
            "Classes",
            "Functions",
            "Conditions"
            ],
        'answer':3
    },
    {
        'question': "Which statement is NOT true",
        'options': [
            "Variables are named memory locations that hold a value",
            "Variables can have local or global scope",
            "Variables cannot be changed once created",
            "Variable should have descriptive names" 
            ],
        'answer':2
    },
    {
        'question': "Which is the proper way to denote a constant",
        'options': [
            "MY_CONSTANT",
            "my_constant",
            "myConstant" 
            ],
        'answer':0
    },
    {
        'question': "Which name is written in snake case",
        'options': [
            "snakeCase",
            "SnakeCase",
            "snake_case" ,
            "snake-case"
            ],
        'answer':2
    },
    {
        'question': "Which name is written in camel case",
        'options': [
            "CamelCase",
            "camelCase",
            "camel_case",
            "camel-case"
            ],
        'answer':1
    },
    {
        'question': "The = symbol in Python is used for assignment, not comparison.",
        'options': ['True', 'False'],
        'answer': 0
    },
    {
        'question': "Python is a case-sensitive programming language.",
        'options': ['True', 'False'],
        'answer': 0
    },
    {
        'question': "The print() function is used to display output to the screen.",
        'options': ['True', 'False'],
        'answer': 0
    },
    {
        'question': "Runtime errors occur before a program is executed.",
        'options': ['True', 'False'],
        'answer': 1
    },
    {
        'question': "A syntax error occurs when Python cannot understand the structure of a statement.",
        'options': ['True', 'False'],
        'answer': 0
    },

    {
        'question': "A semantic (logic) error causes a program to stop running immediately.",
        'options': ['True', 'False'],
        'answer': 1
    },
    {
        'question': "Which data type would best store a person’s age?",
        'options': [
            "str",
            "bool",
            "int",
        "float"
            
        ],
        'answer': 4
    },

    {
        'question': "What does the following statement do?\n\nx = 10",
        'options': [
            "Displays 10",
            "Compares x to 10",
            "Assigns 10 to x",
            "Adds 10 to x"
        ],
        'answer': 2
    },

    {
        'question': "What is the output of:\n\nprint(\"Hello\" + \"World\")",
        'options': [
            "Hello World",
            "Error",
            "HelloWorld",
            "Hello+World"
        ],
        'answer': 4
    },

    {
        'question': "Which function converts a value to an integer?",
        'options': [
            "str()",
            "float()",
            "int()",
            "input()"
        ],
        'answer': 2
    },

    {
        'question': "Which tool helps programmers locate and fix errors?",
        'options': [
            "Interpreter",
            "Debugger",
            "Editor",
            "Compiler"
        ],
        'answer': 3
    },

    {
        'question': "Which of the following is an example of a syntax error?",
        'options': [
            "Incorrect output",
            "Misspelled keyword",
            "Wrong formula",
            "Incorrect logic"
        ],
        'answer': 1
    },

    {
        'question': "Why are comments important in a program?",
        'options': [
            "They improve execution speed",
            "They help the interpreter run code",
            "They provide an explanation of code",
            "They fix errors automatically"
        ],
        'answer': 2
    },

    {
        'question': "Which best represents the basic structure of a program?",
        'options': [
            "Hardware → Software → Output",
            "Input → Processing → Output",
            "Compiler → Interpreter → Debugger",
            "Comments → Errors → Results"
        ],
        'answer': 1
    },
   {
    'question': "A variable used to store whole numbers is typically of type int.",
    'options': ['True', 'False'],
    'answer': 0
    },

    {
        'question': "The data type used to store decimal numbers in Python is called float.",
        'options': ['True', 'False'],
        'answer': 0
    },

    {
        'question': "The program that reads and executes Python code is called the interpreter.",
        'options': ['True', 'False'],
        'answer': 0
    },

    {
        'question': "Python source code is first converted into bytecode before execution.",
        'options': ['True', 'False'],
        'answer': 0
    },



    {
        'question': "Which symbol is used to assign a value to a variable in Python?",
        'options': [
            "==",
            "=",
            ":",
            "->"
        ],
        'answer': 1
    },

    {
        'question': "Errors that occur while a program is running are called __________ errors.",
        'options': [
            "syntax",
            "logic",
            "runtime",
            "semantic"
        ],
        'answer': 2 or 4
    },

    {
        'question': "Which symbol is used to begin a comment in Python?",
        'options': [
            "//",
            "/*",
            "#",
            "--"
        ],
        'answer': 2
    },

    {
        'question': "What is the environment that provides tools to code, compile, link, and debug called?",
        'options': [
            "Interpreter",
            "Virtual Machine",
            "IDE",
            "Compiler"
        ],
        'answer': 2
    }
  
]